Richard Greenfield

Senior Software Engineer

── Ross.Merc.526@gmail.com

+1 406 285 2387

• Seattle, WA, United States

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-greenfield-485a33258/

Summary

As a Senior Software Engineer and also a Full stack Engineer with nearly 9 years of experiences, I have been working on various fields including Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Neural Network. And also, I have deep expertise with Full stack development using various tech stacks.

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Leap Metrics

03/2019 - 01/2023 | Plano, Texas, United States

- Development of the devices and platforms to detect the brain injury with Python, React.js, React native, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS SageMaker, EC2, Lambda, S3, IOT and DynamoDB.
- Development of an application using React.js, Python, Django and PostgreSQL to increase employee consumption of fruit. The focus of the app was mainly user friendliness and speed.
- Cleaned and integrated large sets of structured and unstructured healthcare datasets with PostgreSOL and MongoDB
- Increased the customer traffic by 10% compared to the previous year by refactoring the food delivery system using React.js, TypeScript, Node.js, MongoDB, and AWS, implementing the food recommendation system which used the NLP model, and implementing the real-time chat with chatbot.
- Developed an AI platform that increased revenue by \$15000 in 2 months by training the CNN, LSTM, Transformer and other Sequence models on AWS Services, collaborated with multi-disciplinary product development teams to identify performance improvement opportunities and improved its accuracy, finally integrated with Web & Mobile application as a part of backend.

Senior Software engineer, Braintrust

07/2017 - 03/2019 | San Francisco, California, United States

- Built the engaging dashboard and the ecommerce applications for tracking and forecasting product prices with Vue.js, Python, Django, SQL, Tensorflow and PyTorch.
- Upgraded and maintained both the back-end and front-end systems.
- Development of the scalable web applications and services to handle heavy traffic using React.js,
 Node.js and MongoDB
- Refactored avatar generation system using Stable Diffusion, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS Lambda, AWS S3, AWS ECR and AWS SageMaker.
- Development of Face Verification system using React.js, Python, Django, NoSQL, OpenCV and PyTorch
- Consistently applied best practices for writing clean, secure, readable, and scalable code.
- Participated in the design and implementation of CI / CD and DevOps processes for agile projects and worked with technologies and platforms such as Python, JavaScript, GIT, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Ngnix, Jenkins, AWS, used debugging tools like React-DevTools for faster debugging and reducing debugging time by 50%.
- Participated in meaningful and thorough code reviews.
- Maintained a large web application using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP(Laravel) framework, and automated monthly supplier payments billing cycle using PHP and MySQL. Ran payment programs on a monthly basis and adjusted conditional business logic through a web interface.

Al Engineer /Software Engineer, Shield Al

08/2015 - 07/2017 | San Diego, California, United States

- Development of drones that automatically navigate area with 3D OpenCV, PyTorch, and PySpark.
- Practicing labeling images for YOLOv2 training, developing scripts for computing label characteristics from given JSON inputs and outputting in different formats.
- Exploring real time object detection using Python, C#, Tensorflow and YOLOv2 to implement in the vehicle.

Skills

Web Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel, React.js, Vue.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Django, Flask, Fast API, Spring Boot, GraphQL, Web3, Blockchain

Object Oriented Programming Languages

C++, C#, Python, Java, Solidity, Go, Ruby, Scala

Database Management System

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Oracle RDBMS, DynamoDB, Redshift

Artificial intelligence

Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch, PySpark, Hadoop, OpenCV, NLP

Other Skills

Unix/Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS Lambda, S3,EC2, ECR, SageMaker, EKS, IOT, Gateway API, UI/UX, Ngnix, Terraform, Airflow, DevOps, ETL, Kafka, Git, Jira, Agile, Jenkins, CI/CD

Languages

- English
- Chinese

Education

Bachelor of Science, University of

California, Berkeley 09/2011 – 05/2015

- Was an International Collegiate Programming Contest Challenger, and completed tens of local contests.
- Solved hundreds of difficult algorithms and data structure problems.